#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Full Name Dr. Arya Karunakaran Nair Sreelekha

Nationality Indian Gender Female

**Date of Birth** 22-September-1992 **Contact Number** 00918469038199

Email ID Aryanair.tvm@gmail.com
Address Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala

Languages Known Hindi, English, Malayalam, Tamil, Gujarati

### **SUMMARY**

A budding anesthesiologist with 2 years experience of working in a tertiary care hospital. Seeking to work in a science related field utilizing education and experience while providing an environment for the growth and development of training skills. To work in a professionally and personally fulfilling environment and give best to patient satisfaction. Provides support for surgical/procedural cases by assisting in the preparation and maintenance of patient equipment and anesthesia delivery system before, during, and after anesthesia care.

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Seeking a challenging career that utilizes my skills in area of competence and to be a part of team that contributes to the growth of the organization with commitment and hard work.

#### WORK EXPERIENCES

# **Morning Star Medical Center**

Nov 2022 - July 2023

# **Consultant Anesthesiologist**

Worked as a full-time anesthesiologist performing over 500+ surgeries both elective and emergency cases ensuring optimum patient comfort and safety.

Types of surgeries include but are not limited to: General surgery, Orthopedics, pediatric surgery, obstetrics & gynecology, ENT, Ophthalmology, plastic surgery, Oral surgery.

Attended patients in Critical care units, Cardiac intensive care units, Emergency and Trauma unit for stabilizing the pt, cardiopulmonary resuscitation, invasive blood pressure monitoring, ventilatory management, securing airway including neonatal intubation.

Implemented ERAS protocol reducing patients' hospital stay and improving the patient's overall outcome.

Following multimodal analgesia regime, postoperative pain scores and opioid use are

tremendously reduced.

Conducted anesthesia focused continuing education program to nursing staff helped in knowledge retention and improved collaboration between departments.

Worked in conjunction with clinicians towards assessment of patient's risk, best course of action and treatment as well as other aspects of anesthesia provisions.

# VIMS Care and Cure Hospital

Aug 2022 – Nov 2022

#### **Anesthesia Consultant**

Formulate an effective anesthesia plan for safe and efficient pre-operative patient care. Responsible for management of complex and difficult anesthesia procedures and care for seriously ill patients under supervision and direction of attending.

### **Government Medical College**

Jul 2021 - Aug 2022

#### **Senior Resident**

Practice a supervisory role when appropriate with increased consultative activities. Provided regional blocks, labor epidurals and pain management. Successfully managed Anesthesia for over 1500 surgical cases including complex surgeries ensuring patient safety and optimal outcomes.

# UN Mehta Institute of Cardiology & Research Centre Observership

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

### ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- Determine best medication to use for each patient and administer anesthesia during surgical procedures, monitor patient during procedure and adjust anesthesia accordingly.
- Prescribes pain management medication, records the dosage and type of medication in patient records.
- Provide Anesthesiology and pain management services to patients as directed or required.
- Communicate with patients and families throughout the entire surgical process including preparation and recovery.
- Mentor medical students and residents on various procedures
- Maintain comprehensive records of medical procedures and patient care.
- To create a safe secure and positive healing environment to support the delivery of exemplary health care to all patients, staff and visitors and help in our objective of

- making the institute a center of excellence.
- To attend and treat patients in IPD including ICU, causality, and other inpatient areas under the supervision of physicians and surgeons and closely supervise the work of subordinate doctors, nurses and paramedical staffs.

### **WORK SKILLS**

- Administering anesthesia and analgesia for routine and emergency procedures
- Part of code blue team in casualty
- Ventilatory management of critically ill-patients
- Providing anesthesia and labor analgesiain obstetric patients
- Experienced in working in Covid-19 setup.
- Managed ASA class 1 2 & 3 cases independently and as a team
- Managing patients in ITU HDU ICCU & Neuro care unit
- Good experience in acute and chronic pain management
- Transport of critically ill patients to peripheral hospitals
- Imparting knowledge to peers & juniors

#### **EDUCATION**

| College/school                              | University/Board   | Degree/Standard | Passing<br>Date | Percentage/Pointer |
|---|--------------------|-----------------|-----------------|--------------------|
| Government MedicalCollege                   | VNSGU              | M.D.            | 2021            | 68                 |
| Pushpagiri Institute of Medical<br>Sciences | KUHS               | M.B.B.S         | 2015            | 64                 |
| Vivekodayam boys higher secondary school    | Kerala State Board | 12th            | 2010            | A+                 |
| St.Theresa's girls convent secondary school | Kerala State Board | 10th            | 2008            | A+                 |

### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES / MEMBERSHIPS

- Lifetime member of Indian Society of Anesthesiologist
- Lifetime member of Indian Medical Association
- Attended & certified at "Chronic Pain Management" workshop at Indian Society of Study of Pain, Surat city branch.
- Certificate of CME "Anesthesia in Patients with coexisting diseases"

- Certificate of participation Distress and Suicide Prevention Help Workshop
- Certificate of participation Basic Life Support Workshop

# AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Presented paper on "effectiveness of perfusion index as an early indicator of predicting the successof caudal block in pediatric patients" in ISACON Conference 2021
- Indian Society of Anesthesiologist certificate of appreciation to PPE CLAD COVID WARRIORS
- Gold medalist in Microbiology (UG)

I hereby declare that all the above information is correct with fact or truth up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

Date: 11/11/2023 Arya K.S.